ABHISHEK KUMAR SINGH

SYSTEM ENGINEER

Phone: +91-7667488641 Email: abhisheksingh007@outlook.in Website: https://coderakki.in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-kumar-singh-07/ GitHub: https://github.com/AbhishekKumarSingh07

ABOUT

Abhishek has more than 2 years of technical experience in development in Python, Asp.Net, VB.Net, Oracle database and MS-SQL database. He has experience in maintaining and executing the .NET test automation scripts as well. His area of interest is in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence. He has been doing competitive programming in python for more than 3 years. He had created multiple projects in them as well. All his work is kept at GitHub repo which can be seen either by visiting GitHub or by accessing his website.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FIME, System Engineer

26th May 2021 - Present

Domain: Payment

Key activities performed:

- Understanding the latest payment domain workflow.
- Design test suite for testing tool as per the latest test cases.
- Integrate creation of test cases with latest technologies.

Zensar Technologies, Software Engineer

 $10^{th}\ June\ 2019-20^{th}\ May\ 2021$

Domain: Banking and Finance **Client:** C. Hoare & Co. Bank **Key activities performed:**

- Written Vb.Net code for core application of the bank.
- Python code for running the script.
- Oracle script for database objects, procedure and packages.

EDUCATION

IES College of Technology

RGPV, Bhopal 2015 – 2019 7.71 CGPA

Subhash Public School

CBSE, Giridih 2014 76.6%

Dev Sangha National School

CBSE, Deoghar 2011 9.0 CGPA

CERTIFICATION

Python and Django - Durga Soft Android and Hadoop - Summer Internship Basic Python – HackerRank C (Basic + Intermediate) - HackerRank

AREA OF INTEREST

Artificial Intelligence
Machine Learning
Competitive Coding
Learning New Technology

SKILLS

Language: Python, C++, C, C#, AndroidDatabase: Oracle PL/SQL, MS-SQL, MySQL

Framework: Django, ASP.Net

Tools: VS Code, Fork, Oracle SQL Developer, Visual Studio

Android Studio, Notepad++ Linux (Ubuntu), Windows

Other: HTML, CSS, GitHub, GitLab, TFS

PROJECTS

Jarvis AI:

OS:

- Made Using python, working on integration of ML.
- > Take command and perform operations like:
 - Calculation
 - o Google Search
 - o Weather Report

Data Analysis:

- Created two projects for data analysis:
 - · Using Panda
 - Using MATPLOTLIB
- ➤ Both projects are for the purpose of understanding analysis.
- Planning to integrate this with my other projects.

Portfolio:

- > Created portfolio website in angular and hosted.
- It showcases my work history, interest and other details.
- Purpose of creating portfolio was learning and easy access for others.

Android App:

- Created multiple android application as college projects.
- These applications were for providing students with:
 - Latest Relevant News
 - Online Assessment
 - Direct Communication with Faculties.